<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Time to Geek on Time-to-Geek</title><link>https://yvesdenis.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Time to Geek on Time-to-Geek</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 11:20:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yvesdenis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build, deploy and run an application with ECR, ECS and Codebuild (Part 1)</title><link>https://yvesdenis.github.io/post/ecs-ecr-codebuild-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 11:20:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yvesdenis.github.io/post/ecs-ecr-codebuild-post/</guid><description>Introduction In this article, we will follow the complete development cycle of a real-world application from its conception to its production. Nowadays, the wind of the moment pushes us all to turn to the cloud because in many aspects it offers more advantages compared to on-premises systems.
I decided to divide this tutorial into two parts given its volume, so for this first part, we will focus in more detail on the infrastructure to be deployed and the motivation behind the choice of technologies used.</description></item><item><title>Building a Command line application in Golang</title><link>https://yvesdenis.github.io/post/cli-app-golang-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 23:20:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://yvesdenis.github.io/post/cli-app-golang-post/</guid><description>Introduction Command Line Applications(CLI) are computer programs designed to be used from a text-based interface such as Shell or Bash. They are useful as they allow users to type in commands that can produce immediate results or give them the possibility to automate tasks. Some CLI tools: Git, Brew, Curl, etc&amp;hellip;
I&amp;rsquo;m a CLI lover as are almost all developers :) The feeling of working with the terminal gives you the sensation to be a Hacker (like the hoodie guy in the movies hidden in the dark and playing with his keyboard)</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://yvesdenis.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yvesdenis.github.io/about/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;We used to say, There&amp;rsquo;s nothing cool about being a dummy. Read more at https://www.brainyquote.com/topics/dummy-quotes&amp;quot;
Skills Cloud Architecture Distributed Systems Engineering DevOps Software Developer { Java | Go | Bash | Shell | JavaScript } Big Data Data Structures - Algorithms { Problem-solving } Accounts Github - profile : https://github.com/yvesDenis
Linkedin - profile : https://linkedin.com/in/deffo-yves-denis-bbb275100</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://yvesdenis.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yvesdenis.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Even if it&amp;rsquo;s not obvious I pay attention to outside opinions and yours will surely be relevant.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message</description></item></channel></rss>